I let a candle to open our ceremony tonight again to remind us that who we are and where we came from and what it's all about because that's what you're hearing about to do to learn, isn't it?
Fire can kill, fire can burn, destroy. As a matter of fact, the first fellow of an invented fire, Prometheus, got in a lot of trouble with the FDA running off the moon.
They said, wait a minute, we're going too fast. Maybe we're not ready for fire. As a matter of fact, that's a question that often occurs to many of us these days. Maybe man isn't ready for powerful chemicals like LSD and the many new ones that are coming.
Maybe man's little mind isn't ready at this moment in evolution to deal with too much, too fast in the way of reality. Fire is dangerous. Maybe we should pass a law against it. Maybe we should pick out the livers of everybody that uses it.
So they can't let high school and college children have it. What are you going to do about it? How are we going to keep people from burning themselves up and hurting themselves and killing themselves with fire?
Well, we can ask that training our kids from the time they can listen to us, that fire is here, that water is here, that the lot of energies around that are here that aren't going to go away and they better learn how to use them from the very earliest moments and know what they can do and what they can't do and how they destroy.
Because sometimes when I see what fire is doing to the thin layer of topsoil on this planet, I wonder maybe they were right about Prometheus and maybe the human race isn't ready even now to deal with powers like fire.
Now, it may seem eccentric to you that I come to an Institute of Engineering and Technology and start talking about sacraments and earth and air and fire and water and ceremonies.
But I don't really think it should be that odd. The uniform I'm wearing may be out of date in this particular brief show you have going here but people have been sitting barefoot as I am sitting now in front of you for thousands of years in front of candlelight talking about what I'm talking about, where are we going, what's it all about, what can we do about it, how can we figure it out, how can we tune it back in.
Don't you know that the real, real goal of a scientist is to flip out? Don't you know that? Had you forgotten?
Oh, you thought that the role of a scientist was to build bigger and bigger stage sets for the television show you got going here.
Yeah, we have to have a big road running from the Copson Robbers game here to the cowboy Indian show over there and you engineers are supposed to build them so that we can go faster and faster and farther and farther from television show to television show.
But if you take science seriously and if you take the history of science seriously you'll realize that every great scientist wasn't in it for the TV show commercial payout.
He was in it to find out what it's all about, what's nature of energy, what are the many levels of energy, what are the levels of consciousness, how can we map them out, how can we use them.
And as he got to know more and more and to penetrate deeper and deeper into the mysteries of energy around us he began to flip out, he began to flip out, look at Einstein.
E equals MC squared, come on, you mean that that's all energy? Wow, Einstein did it without LSD.
You have been led to believe most of you that religion is something that's serious and something that's mildly hypocritical and it's really little to do with the basic questions in life, material of science.
Well, the facts matter are that religion is supposed to be fun and ecstasy because you know it's all a play that we're involved in of energy.
And you think that a religious person who goes around the long face reciting the Boy Scout of religion starts as science has always started in the pursuit, the quest for the ultimate questions.
And it's fun, science should be fun, science should be pleasure, science should be flipping out, going out of your mind, really stunned by the joy of this incredible energy situation.
Now, the message I have is an old one, it's the simplest and most classic message you're in passed on in world history, it's those six words, drop out.